Hello Bruce, what are you doing here, eh?
你好 Bruce, 你在这里做什么, 嗯?
I was under the impression
you were in the Central European Zone, Leader.
我得到的印象是, 你还在中欧区, 领袖
That's what you were meant to believe.
那正是要让你们相信的
Why?
为什么？
I do not care to be questioned by my own security!
我不喜欢被我自己的安保人员质问！
Well that's just it. How can I possibly
maintain security when you behave like this?
好我正要说这个．你行为这样, 我怎么能保障安全呢？
I'm at least entitled to know your movements.
我至少有权知晓你的动向吧
You have a policeman's mind, Bruce.
你有一个警察的思维, Bruce
That may be! Only a few days ago you questioned me
about this man and his activities.
可能吧！仅仅几天以前, 你还在问我这个人和他的活动情况
And we agreed that he was dangerous!
Now, I find you in his office.
而且我们都同意他很危险！ 而现在, 我发现你在他的办公室
Sometimes I like to deal with matters in my own way.
有时候我喜欢用我自己的方式处理问题
- They're not holding you here?  - Holding me?
- 不是他们把你扣在这里的？  - 扣住我?
Under some threat or other.
你被威胁了什么的
No one threatens Salamander!
没人可以威胁 Salamander!
I still think I deserve an explanation, Leader.
我还是觉得我需要一个解释, 领袖
Yes, of course, you shall have it.
是的, 当然了, 你会得到的
But not now. When I return from the Central European Zone.
但不是现在．等我从中欧区返回吧
Very well.
那好
Now what about the dead man found in your bungalow.
现在说说在你的平房里发现的死人吧
He was one of your lot, wasn't he?
他是你们当中的一个, 对吧？
Yes. Um, he was trying to protect me.
The other two wanted to kill me.
是的．唔, 他当时在尽力保护我, 另外那两个人想杀我
Now why should they want to do that
to a nice young girl like you?
那为什么他们会对你这样一个年轻女孩儿做那种事情？
Well I...
这个我...
Obviously they thought I was there.
显然他们以为我在那里
You?
你？
Yes, Bruce, just like you,
a lot of people don't like me.
是的, Bruce, 跟你一样, 很多人不喜欢我
Don't get clever with me, Kent!
I've a good mind to...
别跟我耍聪明, Kent! 我倒相信是....
I am prepared to accept his story.
我打算接受他的故事
Well I'm not!
但我没打算！
That's interesting, but not important.
这很有意思, 但并不重要
I accept it! That's all that matters.
我接受！这才是重要的
It's beginning to look as if these people
are working for you now. Is that right?
看起来, 这些人现在为你工作了？是这样吗？
You still dare to question me!
They have information! I shall get it!
你还是敢质问我？他们有情报, 我要得到！
I will see you on my return. Now leave me!
我回去之后会见你, 现在消失吧！
- McCrimmon, you said?  - Aye
- 你叫 McCrimmon, 你说过？  - 是
Well you just watch your step, that's all.
好, 你看好你的步子, 小心点
I never said a word.
我什么也没说啊
Must be the way you look, Jamie.
那肯定是你的样子看起来有问题, Jamie
You were splendid, Doctor.
你太棒了, 博士
Thank you.
谢谢你
That was a dangerous game to play.
这个游戏玩起来很危险
It paid off. All right, are you with us?
还是值得．好了, 你加入我们吗？
I don't know where you stand, Mr Kent.
我并不知道你的立场, Kent 先生
But you and this Salamander are obviously
on opposite sides. That at least is clear.
但你和这个 Salamander 显然是对立的, 这点至少是清楚的
But which side is good? Which side is bad?
And why should I interfere?
但那一方是好的, 那一方是坏的？为什么我要插手？
Well you're the only man who can help save the world.
不过你是唯一可以帮忙拯救世界的
But isn't that what Salamander's trying to do?
但那不是 Salamander 正在努力做的吗？
Don't you understand? Salamander...
你不明白吗？ Salamander...
Just a moment. Jamie, you're unusually quiet,
what do you think?
等一下．Jamie, 你一反常态的安静, 你怎么想的？
Well to save the world,
aye, well it sounds grand, but...
哦, 拯救世界, 是, 这听起来很伟大, 但是...
Oh, we couldn't turn our back
on a challenge like this, Doctor.
哦, 对于这样的事情, 我们不能转身而去, 博士
Well, at least I know you wouldn't.
至少, 我知道你不会的
We don't know anything about these people.
我们对这些人一点都不了解
Astrid saved our lives.
She was wounded because of it.
Astrid 救了我们的命, 她为此还受伤了
- Oh but Jamie, you don't think...
- Look, she was...
- 噢, 但是Jamie, 你不是觉得...  - 嘿, 她是...
Look, we're right about Salamander!
看, 我们对 Salamander 的看法是对的！
It won't take you long to find out for yourselves.
你们不用多久自己就能发现
How do you propose we do that?
你建议我们怎么干这事？
He'll be well guarded for a start.
首先, 他肯定被严密保护着
We can hardly steal into his study
and go through his papers.
我们很难猫进他的书房, 去查阅他的文件
That man, Bruce, said that
he was in the Central European Zone.
那个 Bruce 说过他之前在中欧区
It's a long way from Australia.
从澳洲过去路很远
It's only two hours by rocket.
坐火箭只需要两个小时
You could leave almost at once.
你们可以马上动身
- Oh, what then?  - I've had a plan ...
- 哦, 然后怎样？  - 我之前做了个计划
... for infiltrating into Salamander's
inner circle for some time.
是在某个时候渗透到 Salamander 的小圈子里去
Well I could adapt it for your two friends.
我可以按你的两个朋友修改一下
I can arrange three travel warrants and visas.
Everything you need.
我可以安排三份旅行证和签证, 所有你们需要的东西
Just three?
就三份？
Well one for Astrid, one for you and ah...
哦, Astrid 一份, 你一份, 还有...
- Victoria.  - Of course.
- Victoria.  - 当然了
Oh that's very clever of you.
How can you do that?
哦, 这很不错啊．你怎么可以做到？
I thought you said you had no official position?
我记得你说过你已经没有了正式职位？
We have a contact there.
我们在里面有联络人
He must be a very important person.
他肯定是一个非常重要的人物
He is. Denes, Controller of the Zone.
是的．Denes, 是该区域的控制员
Oh, I see. What about me?
哦, 我明白了．我做什么？
I think we better have a look at
Salamander's research station at Kanowa.
我想我们最好看一下 Salamander 在 Kanowa 的研究站
Yes. Ah, yes, but from a safe distance of course.
是的．啊, 是, 但当然是在一个安全距离来看
This is dreadful news, Salamander.
I still can't believe it.
这是个可怕的消息, Salamander, 我还是不敢相信
Terrible, terrible.
可怕, 太可怕了
I don't say it will happen.
I say it can happen.
我不是说它会发生, 我是说它可能发生
Your Zone is in danger, Denes.
Here, here and here.
你的区域有危险了, Denes．这里, 这里和这里
We've had no trouble for years in those mountains.
这些年那些山都没有出过什么事情
You don't imagine I make it up?
你不是认为这是我编造的吧？
No, no, of course not.
不, 不, 当然不是
Those volcanoes have been dead
since sixteenth century. Fedorin is right to doubt.
这些火山自从16世纪就沉寂了．Fedorin 的疑问是有理由的
A volcano is a strange thing, my friend.
I tell you the truth.
火山是一个奇怪的东西, 我的朋友。我来跟你说说真实情况
It's like a man in the hot sun,
sleeping... still... lifeless.
就像一个在烈日下面的男人, 沉睡...沉寂...毫无生机
Then boom! He wakes full of energy!
I know volcanoes.
然后嘣！他满能量爆发了！我懂火山的
Isn't there a possibility of a...
miscalculation for a few degrees?
有没有可能在计算上有少许几度的偏差?
I'm never wrong.
Every one of my predictions has been accurate.
我从没出错．我每次的预测都证明是准确的
Yes. You're record is good. I don't deny that.
是的, 你的记录保持得很好, 我不否认这个
You are too kind. Now will you listen to me!
承蒙赞许．现在你听我的了？
Leader, the communications...
领袖, 通讯器...
I know! I know! I told you I was not to be disturbed!
我知道！我知道！我跟你说过我不想被打扰！
Yes, Leader.
好的, 领袖
No, wait! No, wait, Fariah, ah?
不, 等等！不, 等等，Fariah, 哈？
- You like some refreshment, perhaps?
- Thank you.
- 你们想要放松一下吧，怎样？  - 谢谢
No, no, not for me.
不不，我就不用了
You're going so soon?
你这么快就要走了？
I must consult my scientific advisors.
我必须找我的科学顾问咨询一下
You still don't believe me?
你还是不相信我？
I believe you sufficiently to want to...
have your information checked.
我对你足够相信，所以我要...核对一下你给的信息
Before I alarm my people unnecessarily.
以免我不必要地惊扰我的人民
Your scientists won't help you.
They don't know. They are amateurs.
你那些科学家帮不了你．他们不懂, 他们太业余
No, Salamander, they are not amateurs.
不, Salamander, 他们不是业余人员
They are very clever men dedicated to their work.
他们都是非常聪明的人，都有各自擅长的工作
But they are men, capable of human error like anybody else.
但他们是人, 就会跟其他人一样犯错
Do what you wish.
Captain!
按你的想法去做吧。队长！
Sir!
是！
Controller Denes is leaving.
控制员 Denes 要走了
Yes, sir.
是, 长官
You will soon see that I am right.
你很快就会明白我是对的
Oh, you will stay, ah? Have a drink.
哦, 你会留下来, 哈？喝一杯
We have a great deal to talk about, you and I.
我们有好多事情需要讨论, 你跟我
Fariah, see to him.
Fariah, 招待一下他
That might be her now. Yes.
那可能是她了。我是
Hello, Giles? This is me, Astrid.
你好, Giles? 是我, Astrid
Right let‘s have it. What's happening?
好跟我们说说，什么情况？
Everything's gone fine so far.
到目前一起都还好
And the rocket arrived right on time in Hungary.
而且火箭准时到达了匈牙利
And Jamie's got his entrance pass
and has started phase one.
Jamie 也拿到了他的准入证，开始了第一阶段
- Do you think the boy can handle it?
- Well I hope so.
- 你觉得那小子能行吗？  - 嗯，我期望如此
My goodness they're a pretty
odd lot though, aren't they?
天哪他们可是相当奇怪的一队人，是吧？
Well actually the Doctor's with me right now.
噢，事实上博士现在跟我在一起
Oh, I am sorry. Oh I know...
I'm sure they'll be fine.
哦，对不起。噢我知道了...我确信他们会没事的
What news of Denes? We must keep him posted
as to what is happening.
Denes 有什么消息？我们必须将情况变化及时通知他
It's all right, we've contacted
and we've arranged to meet.
没事的，我们联系过了，并且安排了一次会面
Be careful, he's pretty well known.
小心点，他可绝对是个公众人物
But what on earth made you
take a job as a food taster?
但到底是什么让你选了试吃食物作为工作？
She was hungry.
她那时很饿
Only thing is, now she has all the food she needs,
唯一的问题是，现在她所需的的食物她都有了
...she has lost her appetite.
Give me a drink!
...她就没胃口了。给我一杯喝的！
You are well protected.
你被保护得很好
Um.
唔
Very well protected.
Be calm. Sit down, drink your drink.
被保护得非常好。冷静，坐下，喝你的酒吧
Ah!
啊！
Thank you for calling the guard.
I was wondering what to do about him.
谢谢你叫来了警卫。我正不知道拿他怎么办呢
Now don't move for that box!
Not if you value your life.
现在别靠近那个盒子！惜命的话就不要
Now all of you, back over there! That's it.
现在你们全部，都退到那边去！就这样
Not as well protected as you think you are, eh?
保护并不像你所以为的那么到位，嗯？
Now when I say duck... Duck, get down!
现在等我说蹲下...蹲下，躲避！
Look at this! What do you do boys, eh?
看看这个! 你们在做什么呢小子们，嗯？
Read? Sleep? It's a fine thing.
看书？睡觉？这都还算好的
Here we have an attempt to destroy me
and where are you?
现在有人试图干掉我，你们在哪儿？
It's not so good, boys.
It's not so good. I'm watching you.
这可不行，小子们。这可不行，我盯着你们呢
Look after him. Better still, get rid of him.
照看他。更好的是，弄走他
- What's all this about. Eh?
- I heard two men talking.
- 这都怎么回事, 嗯？  - 我听见两个人在说话
They said they'd planted a bomb of some kind
in your radio telephone.
他们说他们在你的无线电话中植入了某种炸弹
I tried to warn them at the gates,
but they wouldn't pay any attention.
我试图在门口警告他们，但他们没有注意到
So you break in? How you break in?
于是你闯进来了？你怎么闯进来的？
Well I'm here on holiday with a friend.
哦，我跟一个朋友过来度假
She's very pretty, so the guard
didn't see me slip past him.
她长得非常漂亮，所以我溜过警卫的时候他没看见我
Why didn't you call out and warn me?
I nearly used the radio telephone several times.
为什么你不大喊几声提醒我？我用过了无线电话好几次
Ah you'd have had me shot, most like.
啊你会枪毙了我的，很可能
Why do you risk your skin to save me?
你为什么冒着自己生命危险救我？
Well without you
the Earth hasn't much of a chance, has it?
哦，如果没有你地球就没有多少机会了，对不？
You like to work for me, eh? You like that?
你想为我工作吗，嗯？你想不？
Oh no, you don't have to do that.
I mean, you owe me nothing.
噢不，你不必这么做。我的意思是，你不欠我什么
You're quite right, boy.
你说得很对，孩子
And I'm on holiday.
而且我还在度假
You won't find what I pay you disappointing.
你不会对我的回报失望的
Aye, there's my girlfriend too though.
啊，但还有我的女朋友呢
Oh we might be able to find something for her.
Eh Fariah?
哦，我们可以帮她找点什么工作。嗯，Fariah?
Yes, your chef could use an assistant.
是的，你的主厨需要一个助手
See to it. What do you say, eh?
你落实一下。你怎么说，嗯？
Well I'll give it a go.
哦，我可以试试
But I'll say this though,
your security system's rotten.
但是我还是要说，你的保安系统烂透了
There'll have to be changes.
必须得做出点改变了
Oh what a boy, ah?
哦，多棒的一个小伙，哈？
Fariah, see he gets some proper uniform
instead of this skirt.
Fariah, 给他弄套合适的制服，换掉这个短裙
And bring him and his girlfriend to see me.
然后带他和他的女朋友来见我
Come along then.
那过来吧
What an extraordinary young man.
多个出色的一个年轻人
I prize loyalty very highly, my friend.
我非常看重忠诚度，我的朋友
And I repay it very generously.
Like I do the girl Fariah, eh.
而且我会慷慨回报，就像我对 Fariah 做的，嗯？
I used to love to do this sort of thing when I was a boy.
我还是个小男孩儿时挺喜欢做这种事情
I'm sorry. It was the safest place I could think of.
很抱歉。这是我能想到的最安全的地方
Oh, it's all right. I'm still fit enough.
哦，没事。我还能钻进来
Thank you for getting me the necessary documents.
谢谢你给我拿来这些必要的文件
Have you been successful?
你还顺利吗？
So far. Salamander's swallowed it.
目前还好。Salamander 已经咬钩了
I thought he would.
我料到他会的
The boy's very confident.
The girl, not so much.
那男孩儿很自信。那个女孩儿，就不太行
See, the point is that I'm near enough
to him to pick out something.
看，关键是我现在离他够近，可以挖出些什么了
This was the first time I met Salamander.
这是我第一次跟 Salamander 会面
I must say that you were right about him, Astrid.
我必须说你对他的看法是对的，Astrid
We must get rid of him. He must be stopped.
我们必须干掉他，必须阻止他
He will be stopped!
I'm returning to Giles Kent.
他会被阻止的。我要回到 Giles Kent 那里去了
Can you wait till we can take action?
你能坚持到我们能采取行动吗？
Oh, with a bit of luck, yes.
哦，有点运气的话，可以
Fedorin, would he betray you in some way?
Fedorin, 他会有可能背叛你吗？
I'm trying to think of some reason why he should.
我在尽力思考一些他那样做的理由
But these are all lies, Salamander. Lies, I assure you.
但这些都是谎言，Salamander。是谎言，我向你保证
So you say.
这是你的说法
What are you going to do? My family... my friends.
你打算怎么做？我的家庭...我的朋友
My dear man. My dear Fedorin.
我亲爱的伙计，亲爱的 Fedorin
You don't suppose I intend to
make your swindling public, eh?
你不会是认为我打算把你诈骗的事情公开吧，嗯？
This is... this just an insurance, um.
Sit down, forget it.
这是...这只是一项保险，唔。坐下，忘了它
I tell you what I'm going to do for you.
我跟你说说我打算为你做什么
What?
什么？
You are going to replace Denes
as controller of this Zone.
你将替代 Denes 成为这个区的控制员
But, don't say anything.
I'll know you'll accept.
但，什么也不要说。我知道你会接受的
What do you want?
你想要什么？
I'll tell you. There will be disaster in this Zone.
我会告诉你的。这个区会有一场灾难
I cannot stop the disaster,
我无法阻止这场灾难
but I can come to the aid of this Zone
when it's happened.
但我能在它发生的时候给予这个区帮助
And take over? I see.
然后接管？我明白了
- The Zone would be yours!
- Oh ours, Fedorin, ours.
- 这个区就是你的了！ - 噢，我们的，Fedorin，我们的
It's a partnership I'm offering you.
这是我提供给你的伙伴关系
Either you have half of everything, or you have nothing.
要不然你什么都有一半，要不然你就什么也没有
But there's Alexander Denes.
但还有 Alexander Denes 呢
Oh yes, the popular, well beloved Denes.
哦，是的，受欢迎受爱戴的 Denes
- What a pity.  - Pity?
- 真遗憾啊  - 遗憾？
Oh didn't I tell you, Denes is going to die.
我没有告诉你吗，Denes 就要死了
Mysteriously... an assassin... terrible.
一次神秘的...刺杀...可怕啊
I can't do that! You can't ask me!
我干不了这个！你不能让我这么干！
I think I can ask you to do anything I want.
我想我可以让你做任何事情
My predictions are accurate!
我的预测是准确的！
The entire Eperjes-Tokaj Ranges are in eruption!
整个 Eperjes-Tokaj 区域都在爆发!
Fedorin, come and look. It's very pretty.
Fedorin，过来看看，非常壮观
The history of Hungary is about to be rewritten!
匈牙利的历史就要被改写了
Salamander.
Salamander.﻿
What are you doing here, Bruce?
你在这里做什么，Bruce?
I had a report there was trouble here,
an attempt on your life.
我收到了报告说这里出了岔子，有人试图要你的命
It was nothing. Come and look.
没什么大不了的。过来看看
Terrible. Those poor people.
吓人啊，这些可怜的人
Salamander! What have you done?
Salamander! 你干了什么？
I warned you!
我警告过你！
You couldn't have known!
You've done this somehow yourself!
你不可能知道！肯定是你自己用什么方法干的！
The man is mad! Worse still he is incompetent!
这个人疯了！更糟糕的是他不胜任！
I warned this man that this zone
was in danger of natural disaster...
我警告过这个人这个区有自然灾害危险...
...and he did nothing!
Issued no cautions to the public.
而他什么都没做！连提醒都没对公众发布过
You deliberately allowed your people to suffer and die!
你故意让你的人民遭罪、死亡！
You're a traitor!
你是个卖国贼！
You're a traitor! You contrived this for your own ends.
你是个卖国贼！你为了自己的目的制造了这场灾难
Bruce, I order you to arrest this man.
Bruce，我命令你逮捕这个人
But this is nonsense. Fedorin, you were here.
但这是胡说。Fedorin，你之前也在
You know this is nonsense.
你知道这是胡说
Denes you are too naive.
Denes 你太天真了
At your trial, Fedorin will be
the chief witness against you!
在你的审判会上，Fedorin 将是反对你的主要证人！